<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tealeaf | The Life Alchemist]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/categories/tealeaf/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-02T22:12:42+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.tomohung.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tomo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newbie for Rails Migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/02/02/newbie-for-rails-migration/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T21:46:35+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/02/02/newbie-for-rails-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a newbie for Rails, It&rsquo;s normal to do something stupid.</p>

<h2>Modified migration files after <code>rake db:migrate</code></h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s useless!! Be carful that every migration filename including a timestamp, after running <code>rake db:migrate</code> will re-generate schema.rb. Data in schema.rb will show that the lastest timestamp, if there is no any new migration files newer than this timestamp, <code>rake db:migrate</code> will do nothing. Yes! it&rsquo;s nothing!!</p>

<pre><code class="text normally you should see">==  CreateArticles: migrating ==================================================
-- create_table(:articles)
   -&gt; 0.0019s
==  CreateArticles: migrated (0.0020s) =========================================
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="text schema.rb has been updated, rake db:migrate do nothing">$ rake db:migrate
$ rake db:migrate
</code></pre>

<!--more-->


<p>That&rsquo;s why I got stuck on it for a long time, because I make such a stupid mistake.</p>

<p>So, how about using <code>rake db:drop</code> or <code>rake db:rollback</code>. This is also a not smart choice, because you should consider that there may be some other co-workers are working on the same project. If they also run their migration on their computer, then you modified yourself migration files, or do some database operation like <code>rake db:rollback</code>. These actions will lead to some data error for database.</p>

<h2>Create another new migration file for modified database</h2>

<p>Using <code>rake generate migration do_some_change</code> for chaning database layer. Using another file to show the modified history is much clear. Avoid ambiguous and mess up all update contect in migration files is super important.</p>

<pre><code class="text Add column for posts table">class AddColumnToPosts &lt; ActiveRecord::Migration
  def change
    add_column :posts, :user_id, :interger
  end
end
</code></pre>

<h2>Only use <code>rails generate migration</code></h2>

<p>Don&rsquo;t use <code>rails generate</code> for models or controllers etc. It contains a lot of rails magic. Although most of guide tour (including official guide) use this way. But it&rsquo;s easy to misunderstanding what is wrong for operating database layer and ActiveRecord layer. Take care of this!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tealeaf Course2 Lesson1 Quiz]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/30/tealeaf-course2-lesson1-quiz/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-30T16:13:42+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/30/tealeaf-course2-lesson1-quiz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Answer these quizzes, then updated after watching solution.</p>

<h2>1. Why do they call it a relational database?</h2>

<p>  Relational database can store the relationship between data and data. For example, a table store customer&rsquo;s info, and a table store consuming record, these two table can be associated with another table, to establish the customer&rsquo;s consuming history. There are relationships between data and data in relational database. ex. sqlite, MySQL, PostgreSQL ect.</p>

<blockquote><p>the tables within the database are associated with each other. This association can be created with primary/foreign keys and various syntax.</p></blockquote>

<h2>2. What is SQL?</h2>

<p>  SQL(Structured Query Language), it&rsquo;s domain specific language to manipulate database.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>3. There are two predominant views into a relational database. What are they, and how are they different?</h2>

<p>  There are two associations concepts in relational database:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>1:M
<strong>One to Many</strong> makes target object can associate with many other objects, like one customer can have many consuming records, we can track the customer&rsquo;s consuming history with this association or we can track the record is generated by which customer.</p></li>
<li><p>M:M
<strong>Many to Many</strong> makes target objects can associate with many other objects, like posts can be assign to many categories, and category can assign to many poasts. We also can track target post or target category is assigned to which one.</p></li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>The two predominant views are the data and schema views.
Data view displays like a spreadsheet, with the table columns at the top and rows of data per each object instance.
A schema view shows us the column names and the value type of each column.</p></blockquote>

<h2>4. In a table, what do we call the column that serves as the main identifier for a row of data? We&rsquo;re looking for the general database term, not the column name.</h2>

<p>  Attributes. Column indicate that what the row values mean.</p>

<blockquote><p>We call this the &ldquo;primary key&rdquo;.</p></blockquote>

<h2>5. What is a foreign key, and how is it used?</h2>

<p>  Every row data in a table is included a <strong>primary key</strong>. If we want to associated with other table, we need this primary key to store which row data we wanna to be connected with this one. The store primary key value&rsquo;s column is called <strong>foreign key</strong>.</p>

<blockquote><p>A foreign key is the identifier that connects an association with the models involved. The foreign key is always on the &ldquo;many&rdquo; side and is always in an integer type.</p></blockquote>

<h2>6. At a high level, describe the ActiveRecord pattern. This has nothing to do with Rails, but the actual pattern that ActiveRecord uses to perform its ORM duties.</h2>

<p>  ActiveRecord is mapping the data operation in tables. It substitutes SQL operation and using migration files to define &amp; operate table column.</p>

<blockquote><p>ActiveRecord is a way to access the database. A database table is related to a class. An object of that class is created as a row in the table. This object can have different attribute values shown as the columns in the table. We can create, retrieve, update, and delete the object instances by altering the database table.</p></blockquote>

<h2>7. If there&rsquo;s an ActiveRecord model called &ldquo;CrazyMonkey&rdquo;, what should the table name be?</h2>

<p>  If I&rsquo;m confused with this, I can use <code>rails console</code> mode, to run</p>

<pre><code>"CrazyMonkey".tableize
</code></pre>

<p>  and the answer should be <code>crazy_monkeys</code>.</p>

<h2>8. If I&rsquo;m building a 1:M association between Project and Issue, what will the model associations and foreign key be?</h2>

<p>  in model files
<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>class Project ActiveRecord::Base
</span><span class='line'>  has_many :issues
</span><span class='line'>end&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;class Issue ActiveRecord::Base
</span><span class='line'>  belongs_to :project
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></p>

<p>  in migration files
<code>
class CreateIssue ActiveRecord:Migration
  def change
    create_table :issues do |t|
      t.integer :project_id
    end
  end
</code></p>

<h2>9. Given this code</h2>

<pre><code>class Zoo &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  has_many :animals
end
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>What do you expect the other model to be and what does database schema look like?</li>
</ul>


<p>  There should be antoher class named &ldquo;Animal&rdquo;, and it belongs to Zoo. Animal should at least have name, and a foriegn key to set to zoo id.</p>

<pre><code>class Animal &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  belongs_to :zoo
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code>class CreateAnimal ActiveRecord:Migration
  def change
    create_table :animals do |t|
      t.integer :zoo_id
    end
  end
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>What are the methods that are now available to a zoo to call related to animals?</li>
</ul>


<pre><code class="``">  zoo.animals
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>How do I create an animal called &ldquo;jumpster&rdquo; in a zoo called &ldquo;San Diego Zoo&rdquo;?</li>
</ul>


<p>  If in <code>rails console</code> mode:</p>

<pre><code class="``">  $ zoo = Zoo.create(name: "San Diego Zoo")
  $ animal = Animal.create(name: "jumpster")
  $ zoo.animals &lt;&lt; animal  
</code></pre>

<h2>10. What is mass assignment? What&rsquo;s the non-mass assignment way of setting values?</h2>

<p>With mass assignment, we can do</p>

<p><code>assumption fields: [title, body]</code>
<code>
@post = Post.new(params[:post])
</code></p>

<p>without mass assignment, we need to do this
<code>
@post = Post.new
post.title = "post title"
post.body = "post body"
</code></p>

<h2>11. What does this code do? <code>Animal.first</code></h2>

<p>Query the first data in table <code>Animal</code>.</p>

<blockquote><p>This will return the first row of data for the first Animal instance object in the animals table.</p></blockquote>

<h2>12. If I have a table called &ldquo;animals&rdquo; with columns called &ldquo;name&rdquo;, and a model called <code>Animal</code>, how do I instantiate an animal object with name set to &ldquo;Joe&rdquo;. Which methods makes sure it saves to the database?</h2>

<p>This will make sure it saves to database
<code>
Animal.create(name: "Joe")
</code></p>

<p>And this will work too
<code>
animal = Animal.new(name: "Joe")
animal.save
</code></p>

<h2>13. How does a M:M association work at the database level?</h2>

<p>  There is a join table between two relational tables, and it needs these two tables row data primary key to be its foreign key. For example, there is a join table called post_categories, and it stores two foriegn key named: post_id and category_id.</p>

<blockquote><p>On the database level of a M:M association, we use a join table to support it. Both of the primary models will each have a 1:M association with the join table.
By using the has_many :through technique, we are able to create an indirect M:M association with the two primary models.</p></blockquote>

<h2>14. What are the two ways to support a M:M association at the ActiveRecord model level? Pros and cons of each approach?</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>has_and_belongs_to_many
Chris metioned that this method is deprecated. If you don&rsquo;t need to operate the join table, this method is easy to set up association between two tables. And it&rsquo;s doing a more implicit way.</p></li>
<li><p>has_many through:
You have to define has_many relation with join table, also define has_many through: realtion to both target table and join table. This explicit the way to connect target table and join table. It&rsquo;s much easier to understand all realtionship between tables.</p></li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>has_many :through requires an explicit join model and a join table, but it is more flexible and we can add additional attributes to the join table.
has_and_belongs_to_many doesn&rsquo;t require a join model or a join table, but it is less flexible and we cannot add additional attributes to the join table.</p></blockquote>

<h2>15. Suppose we have a User model and a Group model, and we have a M:M association all set up. How do we associate the two?</h2>

<pre><code class="ruby User.rb">class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  has_many :user_groups
  has_many :groups, through: user_groups
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="ruby Group.rb">class Group &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  has_many :user_groups
  has_many :users, through: :user_groups
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="ruby UserGroup.rb">class UserGroup &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  belongs_to :user
  belongs_to :group
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="ruby create_user_groups.rb">class CreateUserGroups &lt; ActiveRecord::Migration
  def change
    create_table :post_categories do |t|
      t.integer :user_id
      t.integer :group_id
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection to Tealeaf Lesson 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/22/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-4/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T11:59:53+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/22/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://i.minus.com/iS2bpDcNcj44W.jpg">http://i.minus.com/iS2bpDcNcj44W.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;320&#8221;></p>

<p>To be honest, I still feel uncomfortable with this week. From week 3, I learned html &amp; css, to week 4, I learned jQuery &amp; Ajax. It&rsquo;s definitely not enough only rely on Codecademy&rsquo;s course, so I decide to do one more app, tic-tac-toe on wep. I think this should make me more comfortable with these lessons.</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m wrong, ha!! I still get stuck when doing UI and interactive design. Since I already knew that the most important thing at this moment is becoming a robust rails development, I decide to keep my pace and going to next course.</p>

<p>Recap to this course:</p>

<ul>
<li>week 1, basic Ruby program.</li>
<li>week 2, OOP in Ruby.</li>
<li>week 3, <strong>HTTP is stateless</strong>, HTML &amp; CSS, Sinatra, and Bootstrap.</li>
<li>week 4, jQuery and Ajax.</li>
</ul>


<p>One more thing, I thought I could be a full stack web developer before this course, then I knew I&rsquo;m wrong. There are a lot of knowledge in front end.</p>

<p>And now I have to keep focus on back end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection to Tealeaf Week 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/13/reflection-to-tealeaf-week-3/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T22:23:15+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/13/reflection-to-tealeaf-week-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://i.minus.com/ilSTmPNHVpVTm.png">http://i.minus.com/ilSTmPNHVpVTm.png</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;320&#8221;></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s realy a tough week for me, because I&rsquo;m totally new to web development.
There are lots of material need to be done:</p>

<ul>
<li>One new concept book: HTTP <a href="https://www.gotealeaf.com/books/http">https://www.gotealeaf.com/books/http</a></li>
<li>Two new languages: HTML &amp; CSS <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/htmlcss">http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/htmlcss</a></li>
<li>Two new frameworks: <a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/intro.html">Sinatra</a> &amp; <a href="http://getbootstrap.com/">bootstrap</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I think the most important thing in this week is &ldquo;HTTP is stateless&rdquo;.</p>

<p>And using Sinatra show me this property explicit.</p>

<p>Every request in main.rb is independant with each other, using instance variables to store data only survive its scope.</p>

<p>I also write a brief post to memo this property<a href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/14/show-http-is-stateless-by-sinatra/">(HTTP is Stateless)</a>.
Using chache is another way to feel free in thinking programming in the old way.</p>

<p>Though I still use class to complete this assignment, I feel comfortable with this, because I don&rsquo;t need to make a wheel again.</p>

<p>The first struggle in this week is when I saw something like <code>&lt;form action..../&gt;</code>, I have no idea what&rsquo;s this?! because HTML &amp; CSS course in codecademy never metion this. After google that, I found there are plenty of other syntax I didn&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://www.w3schools.com/html/html5_intro.asp">w3shool</a> help me to know more about HTML.</p>

<p>Another struggle is Sinatra, when I first time read the intro, I totally had no idea what those nouns mean. <code>get '/' {}</code> seems not a nature ruby way; what <code>get</code> <code>post</code> are ??</p>

<p>Following with video and implement functions and pages, then I read Sinatra intro again, this time I feel much clear what its said.</p>

<p>Another horrible thing is on viewing video introduce to modern web development. There are so many tools, concepts, languages need to know. Wow&hellip;</p>

<p>To be a web development, I know I have to keep going.
Moving to Lesson 4.</p>

<p>Finally, here is my blog talking about Reflections for tealeaf lessons.
<a href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/categories/tealeaf/">http://www.tomohung.com/blog/categories/tealeaf/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection of Tealeaf Week 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/07/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T08:15:13+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/01/07/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://i.minus.com/ibnRw2O1pxsQam.png">http://i.minus.com/ibnRw2O1pxsQam.png</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;320&#8221;></p>

<p>Although I have some option video not done yet, I want to share some of my reflection.</p>

<p>When I came to lesson 2, first I found that discussion is less than lesson 1 obviously. I think this imply the lesson OOP is harder than before. Thank god I finished three assignments in a week, how I can do this is because:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>As a C++ programmer, OOP concept is also the same in Ruby, like inheritance, polymorphism, composition&hellip;etc. Since I have some experience to OOP, familiar with Ruby&rsquo;s style is not a hard work for me.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gotealeaf.com/books/oo_ruby"><code>Object Oriented Program book</code></a> is fantastic!! I spent one night to read it, then next day I can just start to implement my idea without too much struggles. It clearly explain the relationship between <code>is-a</code> and <code>has-a</code> corresponding to inheritance and mixin.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>And I do fall in love with Ruby, <code>convention</code> is over configuration becomes nature. In lesson 1, it&rsquo;s weird for me to pass a variable into method, but modified or not depends on what actions in the method. Now I start to think it&rsquo;s convenient to decide modified the variable in the method.
<code>attr_accessor</code> is another kind of example, default getter and setter helps a lot to reduce typing time.</p>

<p>Using polymorphism, I don&rsquo;t need to care about how using virtual function, just inheritance class then use it.
Especially for method <code>super</code>, the best way to reduce redundant code.
One suggestion, If subclass&rsquo;s initialize method doesn&rsquo;t use super, then you might think the superclass and subclass relationship is <code>has-a</code>, not <code>is-a</code>.</p>

<p>I do love my <a href="https://github.com/tomohung/tealeaf/blob/master/Lesson2/oo_tic_tac_toe.rb">Tic-Tac-Toe</a> and <a href="https://github.com/tomohung/tealeaf/blob/master/Lesson2/oo_blackjack.rb">Black Jack</a> implemented by OO. In Tic-Tac-Toe, I use polymorphism to implement single player and double players mode. In Black Jack, I add feature that player can play with others NPC together, not just with dealer. This make the game likely in the real world. Without OO concept, these features are hard to implement.</p>

<p>Next lesson is absolutely my challenge, because I&rsquo;m totally new for web development.
But I do look forward to it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
