<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tealeaf | The Life Alchemist]]></title>
  <link href="http://tomohung.github.io/blog/categories/tealeaf/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tomohung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-02T07:07:18+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://tomohung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tomo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection to Tealeaf Lesson 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomohung.github.io/blog/2015/01/01/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-1/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T16:03:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomohung.github.io/blog/2015/01/01/reflection-to-tealeaf-lesson-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy new year!!</p>

<p>Before I talk about where I struggled with, I would like to say something before I join the course.
I am using C++ for few years, and coding is part of my job. Before join the course, I&rsquo;ve also done the <a href="http://learnrubythehardway.org/book/">Learn Ruby The Hard Way</a> to lesson 45. <code>Learn Ruby The Hard Way</code> is also a good pratice, especially for <code>muscle memory</code>. It focus on <code>just typing ruby</code> when learning ruby knowledge.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>After that, I start <code>Prep Course</code> @ tealeaf, reading the book <code>Introduce to Programing</code>. <code>Introduction to Programing</code> is also an amazing book, it use a simple way to explain more detail in ruby, and I really did several times &ldquo;Ah ha!&rdquo; when reading it. Then I thought I was ready for lesson 1, but maybe I&rsquo;m wrong :p</p>

<p>About my struggles, as a C++ programmer, there are mainly two &ldquo;What?&rdquo; for ruby:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>variable scope: in C++, every local variable only survive in its scope, but in ruby, this is not always true. Even now, I&rsquo;m still a little confused with that. Glad that I find a way to deal with this: <code>Never use outside variable in insdie scope, make them in different name</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>pointer &amp; reference: when passing a variable to functions(in ruby called: methods), if varaible has prefix like <code>*</code> or <code>&amp;</code>, it obvious means this variable may be modified in this methods. Ruby doesn&rsquo;t take this way, input variables in method could be modified just by what action do inside the method. Fotunately, ruby usaually append suffix <code>!</code> behind method&rsquo;s name to indicate this method modify input variable.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Even these, I do love ruby.</p>

<ul>
<li>There are a lot of built-in convenient methods for String, Array, Hash&hellip;etc. And more are waiting to discover</li>
<li>More fluent phrase for flow control, if, unless, while, until&hellip;etc. Readable code is becoming more and more important.</li>
<li>type less key :p</li>
</ul>


<p>And special Thanks for TA&rsquo;s:
Without their help, I couldn&rsquo;t finished these assignments on time. Because of unfamiliar with ruby methods, wrong code style, improper naming&hellip;etc. They always give me timely advice.</p>

<p>Last, share my experience for developing game <code>Black Jack</code>:</p>

<ul>
<li>write psuedo code : 10 min</li>
<li>coding : 2 hours</li>
<li>debugging : 2 hours more</li>
<li>feedback from TA, then refactor: 2 hours</li>
</ul>


<p>By the way, the most difficulty in Lesson 1 is completing &ldquo;Tic-Tac-Toe&rdquo; AI, it tooks me 10 hours more.
If you are totally new to program, don&rsquo;t be disppointed at spending a lot of time, because me too!!
If you are take these assignment as piece of cake, well, let&rsquo;s move to Lesson 2. See you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
