<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Interview | The Life Alchemist]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/categories/interview/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-18T22:01:48+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.tomohung.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tomo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview Review After Tealeaf]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/07/26/interview-review-after-tealeaf/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-26T07:07:25+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.tomohung.com/blog/2015/07/26/interview-review-after-tealeaf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s a late post since I got a Rails job for 2 month. I&rsquo;ll share my background and my interview experience, hope it will be helpful if you have the similar background like me.</p>

<p>Background:</p>

<ul>
<li>From Taiwan</li>
<li>Have 8 years for vision inspection machine development, it needs some of coding work by using C++.</li>
<li>But with NO any experience for web development.</li>
<li>Seek for a career change from a local-based develop a machine for manufacture industry to a cloud-based develop a user experience service.</li>
<li>Start Tealeaf course from last December Christmas and finish it in the early May. ( finish the course on schedule)</li>
<li>Start a Rails working on June.</li>
</ul>


<p>First, let me show the conclusion first:</p>

<ul>
<li>Join Tealeaf Academy is definitely worthy.</li>
<li>Finish the Interview Prep is definitely worthy.</li>
<li>Write blog for this course is definitely worthy.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>Unfortunately, there&rsquo;re not too much job opportunities in Taiwan. This is true, but on the other hand, there are also not too much people really good at Rails. I mean, Rails is popular and well-known, but most people just finish some tutorials from free course like code school or some one day workshop like Rails girls. What we different is &ndash; this is a great opportunity to show your ambitious why you want to &ldquo;PAY&rdquo; for Tealeaf to upgrade your Rails skill. This is always the first question when I talk with interview officer.</p>

<p>I only got 4 interview chances in two month, two of them on April after finishing course 2 and the other two on May after finishing course 3. The Interview Prep is very very very helpful because I am asked for the exactly same questions from there!! Something like security probelm: csrf, authenticity token, or Rails architecture: MVC, OR Mapping, Ruby: polymorphism&hellip;etc. Even that example for association of person and children and grandson :-)</p>

<p>Doing Interview Prep is also a good chance to review what I knew and what I don&rsquo;t know. For example: n + 1 queries and eager loading.</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;m not a native in English, so choosing a English-based course is also an impressing action. Same for writing blogs what I learned from Tealeaf course. I got an unexpecting interview chance from a foreigner company which offer higher payment than others, just because my blog is impressing to them.</p>

<hr />

<p>Hope these will be helpful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
